RAJ KUMAR SHAHU

921-240 Wellesley St. E, Toronto, ON, M4X 1G5
Phone: 647-302-7237 | Email: rajkumarshahu@gmail.com
LinkedIn: https://www.linkedin.com/in/rajshahu/ | GitHub: https://github.com/rajkumarshahu
Portfolio: https://rajkumarshahu.com/

SUMMARY

Full Stack Web Developer with background of biology. Acquired hands-on experience in all aspects of computer programming including, professional communications, administrative duties and computer hardware and networking through the combination of training and hard work. Consistently displayed both an aptitude and an enthusiasm for the task at hand throughout practical and academic courses. Effective at combining creativity and problem solving to develop user-friendly applications. Known among team members for strong wit and attention to detail no matter the complexity of the project.

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Languages: HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, Java, Python Libraries and Framework: ReactJS, Sequelize, Express.js

Database Management: MySQL, MongoDB

Server Environment: Node.is

Collaborative Tools: GitHub, Agile Methods

PROJECTS

Event Hunter

- **GitHub:** https://github.com/bootcampcoder/project-1
- **Deployment:** https://bootcampcoder.github.io/project-1/
- About: Finds nearby free events that can be viewed in calendar and google map
- Role: Designed UI as a Frontend developer. Additionally, implemented Firebase Authentication and integrated backend code with frontend.
- Tools / languages used: JavaScript, jQuery, Firebase Authentication, materialize, bootstrap, HTML, moment.js and Google Maps.

Mood Tracker

- **GitHub:** https://github.com/rajkumarshahu/4-devguys-project
- **Deployment**: https://intense-hamlet 53439.herokuapp.com
- **About:** Uses polarity of emojis to keep record of users' emotions at particular time. Capable of saving and showing emotion status of a user in the form of graph.
- **Role:** Created login system and implemented Sequelize, a database ORM to interface with MySQL database.
- Tools / languages used: JavaScript, jQuery, Handlebars.js, HTML, CSS3, Bootstrap, Chart.js, Sequelize, MySQL, Node.js, Express.js, emoji-emotion-npm.

Link to Lift

- **GitHub:** https://github.com/Indian-Indepth/link-to-lift
- **Deployment:** https://link-to-lift.herokuapp.com/
- About: Capable of connecting personal trainer to trainee and keep track of trainee progress.
- Role: Designed UI as a Frontend developer. Additionally, integrated backend code with frontend.
- Tools / languages used: JavaScript, ReactJS, Google Authentication, Bulma, Node.js, Express.js, MongoDB, Braintree payments platform.

EXPERIENCE

Security Guard 2013 – 2017

Defender Security Toronto, Canada

Performed patrol duties within assigned areas to guard against theft, vandalism and fire and prepared detailed reports and records.

Key Accomplishments:

- Prevented vandalism several times by being vigilant and chasing away vandals.
- Communicated with construction workers and explained the safety rules.

Customer Assistant 2012 – 2013

TescoLondon, UK
Participated in the day-to-day running of the shop that included assisting customers, receiving

Key Accomplishments:

- Answered customer queries effectively to give them best shopping experience
- Handled cash, cheques and credit/debit cards

deliveries, unpacking and re-shelving or storing stock

Supervisor 2009 – 2012 Marsh Wholesale Europe Ltd London, UK

Marsh Wholesale Europe Ltd
Supervised a team of more than 20 staff who worked in production
Key Accomplishments:

- Communicated effectively among the staff to meet deadline.
- Promoted products to maximize sales

Coordinator and Content Director Midas Technologies

2003 - 2009

Midas Technologies Kathmandu, Nepal Coordinated technical and nontechnical staffs while writing and finalizing contents

Key Accomplishments:
Wrote and finalized content for more than 35 multimedia based interactive educational

- Wrote and finalized content for more than 35 multimedia based interactive educational software that are developed using Macromedia Flash.
- Participated in promoting the products during exhibitions

EDUCATION

U of T SCS Coding Boot Camp: U of T School of Continuing Studies, Toronto, ON, Canada A 12-week full-time intensive program focused on gaining technical programming skills in HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, jQuery, Bootstrap, Firebase, Node Js, MySQL, MongoDB, Express, Handelbars.js & ReactJS.

Computer Programmer Analyst: George Brown College, Toronto, ON, Canada A 3-year full-time program with the coursework focused on Programming and Software design with emphasis on HTML5, CSS3, JavaScript, C#, Java, Python, ReactJS, Agile methodologies and so on

Master of Business Administration: Cardiff Metropolitan University, LSC campus, London, UK A 1-year full-time program with the coursework emphases on Marketing, Corporate Finance, Management Information System, Project Management and Strategic Management

Master's Degree in Zoology: Tribhuvan University, Kathmandu, Nepal Major: Parasitology; Minor: Microbiology; Epidemiology, Physiology, Biostatistics and Molecular Biology